<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mike Denham</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mike Denham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Confounding and Aliasing</title>
      <link>/post/understanding-confounding-and-aliasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/understanding-confounding-and-aliasing/</guid>
      <description>Statistical terminology can be confusing. The terms confounding and aliasing were introduced by different researchers at different times during the development of experimental design theory. The two terms were introduced in subtly different contexts. The term confounding was introduced in the late 1920s by Ronald Fisher in the context of blocking experiments. It was used to describe the situation of deliberately “confounding” effects due to differences in blocks with typically higher order interactions between experimental factors to keep the size of a block to a manageable number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding marginality and effect hierarchy, sparsity &amp; heredity</title>
      <link>/post/understanding-marginality-and-effect-hierarchy-sparsity-heredity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/understanding-marginality-and-effect-hierarchy-sparsity-heredity/</guid>
      <description>Did I mention that statistical terminology can be confusing? This is another set of terms that seem to get used somewhat interchangeably. Again I believe there are some subtle (and this time important) differences in their meaning and implications.~McCullagh and Nelder used the term “marginality” in their seminal work on generalised linear models. Their idea has its roots in Taylor series expansions.
To illustrate let’s temporarily imagine a world with no statistical error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>